clipcanvas.com 2019-05-06

# Data Privacy Policy - GDPR | Clipcanvas Support

This post written by  in Monday, August 20th 2018 with Comments Off on Data Privacy Policy – GDPR   

**To all users of our website**

Based on the European General Data Protection Regulation, we have established our policy that covers how we;

  * Collect
  * Use
  * Disclose
  * Transfer
  * Store
  * Delete

… your user data.

Read through this information and if you have any questions, please contact: [gdpr@Clipcanvas.com](mailto:gdpr@Clipcanvas.com;)

  1. General Terms and introduction  
Clipcanvas AS is committed to protecting your personal information when you are using Clipcanvas web services. We want our services to be safe and useful for our clients and users. This Privacy and Cookies Policy relates to our use of any personal information we collect from you via the following online services: 
    * any Clipcanvas website from Clipcanvas
    * any Clipcanvas representation in social media
    * any Clipcanvas mobile device

It also relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us by phone, SMS, email, in letters and other correspondence.  
In order to provide you with the full range of Clipcanvas services, we sometimes need to collect information about you.  
This Privacy and Cookies Policy explains the following:

    * what information Clipcanvas may collect about you
    * how Clipcanvas will use information we collect about you
    * when Clipcanvas may use your contact information to contact you
    * your choices regarding the personal information you provide to us
    * the use of cookies on Clipcanvas websites and how you can reject cookies
    * how to delete your collected information

Clipcanvas is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all applicable laws concerning the protection of personal information, including the Data Protection Act 1998 (these laws are referred to collectively in this Privacy and Cookies Policy as the “data protection laws”).  
Clipcanvas websites contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, and are also likely to use cookies, and we therefore urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit when visiting these websites, which may also be collected by cookies. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

  2. Who are we?  
Clipcanvas is a leading provider of High Quality Stock Video to the global market. 

**Our online services**  
We have a international  website www.Clipcanvas.com, and country sites for many of our local markets. When we refer to ‘’we’’ or ‘’our’’ or ‘’Clipcanvas’’ we are referring to all web and mobile solutions we operates in the global market. 

  3. What information will Clipcanvas collect?  
When you participate in, access or sign up to any of the Clipcanvas services, activities or online content, such as newsletters, live chats, message boards, web and mobile notifications, telephone or text Clipcanvas, or leave contact information by filling out our online contact forms. This can consist of information such as your name, employer, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number, as well as information collected about your use of Clipcanvas services. 

Please note that sometimes we will require you to provide additional personal information. When we do this we will provide further information about why we are collecting your information and how we will use it.

Clipcanvas collects information about how you use Clipcanvas websites. This includes collecting unique online identifiers such as IP addresses, which are numbers that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet. We also collects information on the video clips that you are clicking on and/or downloading as well as search terms used. For more information, please see section Cookie settings, on the Clipcanvas’ use of cookies and similar technologies.

  4. How will Clipcanvas use the information?  
Clipcanvas will use your personal information for a number of purposes including the following: 
    * to provide our services, activities and online content, to provide you with information about them and to deal with your requests and enquiries.
    * to provide you with the user-friendly online navigation experience.
    * for “service purposes”, which means that Clipcanvas may contact you for reasons related to the service, activity or online content you have signed up for, as set out in section 5 below (e.g. to provide you with password reminders, to notify you that a particular service, activity or online content has been suspended for maintenance, to notify you of updates to our Privacy and Cookies Policy or Terms of Use.
    * where we provide personalized services, we may analyze the information you supply, as well as your activity on our (and other) services, so that we can offer a more relevant, tailored service.
    * to contact you about a submission you have made, including any content you provide. For additional information, please see the Terms of Use.
    * to use IP addresses and device identifiers to identify the location of users, to block disruptive use, to establish the number of visits from different countries.
    * for analysis and research purposes so that we may improve the services offered by Clipcanvas.
    * we may also use and disclose information in aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) for marketing and strategic development purposes.

Where Clipcanvas proposes using your personal information for any other uses we will ensure that we notify you first. Please see section 6 below for details. 

  5. Your Clipcanvas Account  
If you have registered for a Clipcanvas account this will also allow you to login to apps and services. 

Your Clipcanvas account will always be covered by the policies of this website. 

  6. When will the Clipcanvas contact me?  
Clipcanvas may contact you:  
in relation to any service, activity or online content you have signed up for in order to ensure that Clipcanvas can deliver the services to you, e.g. to verify your email when you sign up for a Clipcanvas account, or to help you reset your password.  
in relation to any correspondence we receive from you or any comment or complaint you make about Clipcanvas products or services.  
in relation to any personalized services you are using.  
to invite you to participate in surveys about Clipcanvas services.  
to update you on any material changes to the Clipcanvas policies and practices.  
We will never contact you to ask for your Clipcanvas account password, or other login information. Please be cautious if you receive any emails or calls from people asking for this information and claiming to be from Clipcanvas. 
  7. Will I be contacted for marketing purposes?  
Clipcanvas will only send you marketing emails or contact you on Clipcanvas platforms where you have agreed to this. We may personalize the message content based upon any information you have provided to us and your use of Clipcanvas services. 
  8. Will the Clipcanvas share my personal information with anyone else?  
We will keep your information within Clipcanvas except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies, including for child protection reasons) or as described in this section and section XX.  
Generally, we will use your information within Clipcanvas and will only share it outside Clipcanvas where you have requested it or given your consent. 
  9. How long will Clipcanvas keep my information?  
We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with Clipcanvas. If you delete your Clipcanvas account then your personal information is deleted immediately, and the remaining information is anonymized for analytical purposes. 

Where you contribute content together with your personal information (User Generated Content) please refer to our Terms of use for further information about how long we may store such material. 

  10. Can I delete my data?  
You can always delete your Clipcanvas account. This is done via self service or e-mail, by taking contact: support@Clipcanvas.com 
  11. Can I find out what personal information Clipcanvas holds about me?  
Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to request a copy of the personal information Clipcanvas holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. We will use reasonable efforts consistent with our legal duty to supply, correct or delete personal information about you on our files. 
  12. Web browser cookies

**a) What is a Cookie?**  
A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer, tablet or mobile phone (all referred to here as a “device”) web browser from a website’s computer and is stored on your device’s hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your web browser if your browser’s preferences allow it. Many websites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows. Similar technologies are also often used within emails to understand whether the email has been read or if any links have been clicked. If you continue without changing your settings, we’ll assume that you are happy to receive all cookies on Clipcanvas websites. However, you can change your cookie setting at any time.

On Clipcanvas websites, cookies record information about your online preferences and allow us to tailor our websites to your interests.

During the course of any visit to a Clipcanvas website, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. Many websites do this, because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like find out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.  
**b) How does Clipcanvas use cookies?**  
Information supplied by cookies can help us to understand the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience. It also helps us recognize when you are signed in to your Clipcanvas account and to provide a more personalized experience. For example, if on a previous visit you went to our education pages, we might find this out from your cookie and highlight educational information on your second and subsequent visits. Clipcanvas uses this type of information to help improve the services it provides to its users. Certain areas of Clipcanvas websites may use cookies for a specific reason.  
**c) Third party cookies in embedded content on Clipcanvas pages**  
Please note that during your visits to Clipcanvas websites you may notice some cookies that are not related to Clipcanvas.  
To support our content, we sometimes embed content from social media and other third party websites. These may include YouTube, Twitter, Facebook, SoundCloud, Vine, Instagram, Pinterest, Flickr and others . As a result, when you visit a page containing such content, you may be presented with cookies from these websites and these third party cookies may track your use of Clipcanvas website. Clipcanvas does not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party’s website for more information. If you continue without changing your settings, we’ll assume that you are happy to receive all cookies on Clipcanvas website. However, you can find out about changing your cookie settings here…  
Where Clipcanvas embeds content from social media and other third party websites, some websites may use Google Analytics to collect data about user behaviour for their own purposes. Clipcanvas does not control this. For more information, see the Google webpage “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps”.  
**d) Clipcanvas cookies and how to reject cookies**  
Full information about how Clipcanvas uses cookies, and how to control what cookies are set on your device through Clipcanvas website, can be found on xxx.  
It is important to note that if you change your settings and block certain cookies, you will not be able to take full advantage of some features of Clipcanvas services, and we might not be able to provide some features you have previously chosen to receive.  
**e) Other information collected from web browsers**  
Your web browser may also provide Clipcanvas with information about your device, such as an IP address and details about the browser that you are using. We use information provided by your browser or by the link that you have clicked to understand the webpage that directed you to Clipcanvas and this may be captured by performance cookies.  
If you have any concerns about the way that we use cookies or respect your settings, then please contact us at [gdpr@Clipcanvas.com](mailto:gdpr@Clipcanvas.com;). 

  13. Do Not Track (DNT) browser setting  
DNT is a feature offered by some browsers which, when enabled, sends a signal to websites to request that your browsing is not tracked, such as by third party ad networks, social networks and analytic companies. This website does not currently respond to DNT requests. 
  14. Apps and Devices  
When you download or use Clipcanvas apps on your mobile device, information may be accessed from or stored to your device. Most often this is used in a similar way to a web browser cookie, such as by enabling the app to ‘remember’ you or provide you with the content you have requested.  
Your web browser or device may also provide Clipcanvas with information about your device, such as a device identifier or IP address. Device identifiers may be collected automatically, such as the device ID, IP address, MAC address, IMEI number and app ID (a unique identifier relating to the particular copy of the app you are running).  
If you have any concerns about the information which might be accessed from or stored on your device by Clipcanvas, you may wish to only access Clipcanvas content through a web browser and review your web browser settings. 
  15. Changes to the Clipcanvas Privacy and Cookies Policy  
This Privacy and Cookies Policy may be updated from time to time so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to Clipcanvas. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use Clipcanvas websites to submit personal information to Clipcanvas. If material changes are made to the Privacy and Cookies Policy, for instance affecting how we would like to use your personal information, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Privacy Policy changes). 
  16. Contacting Clipcanvas about this Privacy and Cookies Policy  
If you any questions or comments about this Privacy and Cookies Policy please contact:  
Email:[gdpr@Clipcanvas.com](mailto:gdpr@Clipcanvas.com;)

Filed Under: [Legal](https://support.clipcanvas.com/category/legal/)       Tags: [Privacy Policy](https://support.clipcanvas.com/tag/privacy-policy/)
